The Secret Kingdom is a adventure, family, fantasy
film directed by Matt Drummond.
Verity and Peter’s trip to the old family mansion takes a turn when the floor of their room suddenly gives way
and they fall into an underground chamber where they are met by a civilization of creatures.
The leader tells them that Peter's arrival was foretold as he’s the one who can use Great Clock of the
Citadel to restart time and destroy the Shroud, a malevolent creature who feeds on fear itself...
Peter, played by Sam Everingham.
Verity, played by Alyla Browne.
Viviane Drawmer, played by Alice Parkinson.
Ego, played by Beth Champion.
David Drawmer, played by Christopher Gabardi.
Pling, played by Darius Williams.
The Secret Agent (Portuguese: O Agente Secreto; Brazilian Portuguese: [u aˈʒẽt͡ʃi seˈkɾɛtu]) is a 2025
neo-noir historical political thriller film written and directed by Kleber Mendonça Filho.
It follows Armando (Wagner Moura), a former professor caught in the political turmoil in the midst of the
Brazilian military dictatorship, attempting to flee persecution and resist an authoritarian regime.
The supporting cast includes Carlos Francisco, Tânia Maria, Robério Diógenes, Maria Fernanda Cândido,
Gabriel Leone, Alice Carvalho, Hermila Guedes, Isabél Zuaa, and Udo Kier in his final film role.
The film had its world premiere at the main competition of the 2025 Cannes Film Festival on 18 May, where it received widespread acclaim and became the festival's most
awarded film, winning the Best Actor award for Moura, the Best Director award for Mendonça Filho, the Art House Cinema Award and the FIPRESCI Prize for Best Film.
At the 83rd Golden Globe Awards, it became the first Brazilian film nominated for Best Motion Picture – Drama,
winning Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Drama (Wagner Moura) and Best Foreign Language Film.
At the 98th Academy Awards, it has been nominated for Best Picture, Best Actor
for Moura, Best Casting and Best International Feature Film.
It was theatrically released in Brazil and Germany on 6 November 2025 by Vitrine Filmes and Port au
Prince Films, respectively, and was released in France on 17 December by Ad Vitam.
The film explores themes of underground world, child
hero, chosen one, dragon, fantasy world.